[Music]
hey guys
IRA Myers here with power of the land
ministries and this is my promise to
follow up video to is Aretha Franklin in
heaven in this video I'm gonna be
addressing this unusual question are the
Dead still alive so why this follow-up
video well after posting the first video
I began getting some responses from
people claiming that Aretha Franklin and
others who have died are actually alive
and well in heaven or alive and not so
well in hell so you may think I'm joking
but I'm not most of these responses come
from well-meaning Christians who have
quoted 2nd Corinthians 5 6 to 8 absent
from the body present with the Lord as
well as the story of Lazarus and the
rich man found in Luke 16 as proof or
evidence that people are alive in heaven
or hell right now so I promise to make a
follow-up video addressing these two
verses and the idea that the dead are
really alive
so listen the definition of death is the
cessation of life right it is the
opposite of life the ability to think
feel no function the ability to breathe
all come to an end this is what happened
to Aretha Franklin John McCain Mac
Miller and every other person who has
died a person cannot be both dead and
alive at the same time think of it like
this a thing cannot both exist and not
exist simultaneously something cannot be
both hot and cold or wet and dry or
heavy and light at the same time that's
an impossibility
so either the dead are dead or they are
alive and not dead but they can't be
both at the same time
listen faith does not call for the
suspense
of reason okay let's take a two question
quiz right question number one if I were
to ask a Christian right a believer in
Christ if Jesus Christ is alive or dead
what do you think the answer would be of
course they'd say he's alive
why because though he died he was
resurrected or brought back to life
right and the empty tomb was also
evidence that jesus is alive right had
the body of Jesus been found it would
have proved that he was not alive
correct so Jesus is not dead and alive
he was dead but now is alive he was dead
for three days and is no longer dead
correct okay so far so good now question
number two Abraham Lincoln Michael
Jackson your great-great great-great
grandparents dead or alive
what's your answer okay most likely you
said the right answer
dead why because they are no longer
alive do you see what I'm saying all
right now here's where things begin to
get really confusing people will claim
that those who are dead are absent from
the body and present with the Lord or
present in hell that means that while
the body is in the grave a fact that
cannot be disputed the spirit supposedly
lives on either in heaven or hell
the spirit therefore doesn't die right
in this sense a person is dead and alive
hmm see that defies logic and reason
because something cannot be two opposite
things at once something cannot be dead
the cessation of life and alive the
continuation of life at the same time
this is a contradiction in thought and
common sense it demands the suspension
of Reason science nature and it
contradicts what the Bible actually
teaches about this subject so let me lay
out a few points right many paranormal
shows have become popular lately where
the hosts appear to be hunting down or
communicating with the day first the
Bible clearly prohibits the act of
trying to communicate with the day in
Deuteronomy 18 verse 10 the Bible says
there shall not be found among you
anyone that maketh his son or his
daughter to pass through the fire or
that uses divination or an observer of
times or an enchanter or a witch or a
charmer or a consultor with familiar
spirits or a wizard or a necromancer so
what is a consulted with familiar
spirits well that was one who claimed to
have the ability to communicate with the
dead they were called familiar spirits
because these spirits masqueraded as
departed loved ones pretending to be
alive in the afterworld listen if the
dead are really still alive able to
breathe they feel and communicate on
another plane of existence then why
would God prohibit us from communicating
with them right think about that why
would God put a prohibition on talking
to people who are now alive in heaven
okay Jesus is in heaven we can talk to
him alright the Bible puts no
prohibition on the communication with
angels so we can talk to angels we can
talk to Jesus but not to people who are
alive in heaven listen whether you're a
Christian or not it's important to
understand what the Bible actually
teaches on this subject so allow me to
dismantle this popular error that the
dead are really still alive first the
Bible tells us that man does not possess
a soul but that he is a soul in Genesis
2:7 the Bible says and the Lord God
formed man of the dust of the ground and
breathed into his nostrils the breath of
life and man became a living soul God
did and breathed into him some intimate
immaterial spirit he breathed into him
the breath of life
listen body plus breath equals a soul a
soul is simply a living being this is
why the Bible describes even animals as
Souls
in speaking of the prohibition on eating
the blood of animals the Bible says in
genesis 9:4
but the flesh with the life thereof that
word life is the same word for soul the
flesh with the life thereof you shall
not eat see the Bible calls animals
Souls why because they are living beings
in numbers 5 verse 6 the Bible says
speak unto the children of Israel when a
man or woman shall commit any sin that
men commit to do a trespass against the
Lord and that person be found guilty
again that word for person is the same
word used for soul so a person is a soul
a person does not have a soul as some
separate entity like Hollywood often
portrays right listen to this verse Joe
27 verse 3 the Bible says all the while
my breath is in me and the Spirit of God
is in my nostrils
that's the breath of life job 33 verse 4
the Spirit of God has made me and the
breath of the almighty has given me life
it is the Spirit of God that gives us
breath remember that now let's see how
God Himself defined death in Genesis
2:17 the Bible says but the tree of the
knowledge of good and evil thou shalt
not eat of it for in the day
eatest thereof thou shalt surely die now
check this out the serpent comes to Eve
in the garden and says to her Genesis 3
verse 4 you shall not surely die the
first lie ever told in the Bible is that
man could not die but instead he would
be like God immortal self-sustaining
you see it's no wonder almost all
religions have this teaching that the
dead don't really die as their
foundation from the New Age movement too
many Christian beliefs to Eastern
religions almost all adhere to some form
of belief in a soul which cannot die
almost all teach some form of this first
lie spoken by Satan so Adam and Eve eat
from the tree and when God speaks to
them of their punishment listen to what
he says listen to how he defines death
in Genesis 3:19 he says these words in
the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat
bread till thou return unto the ground
for out of it was thou taken for dust
thou art and unto dust shalt thou return
death is a return to the condition in
which you were in before you came to
life death is a return to the state that
they were in Adam and Eve before they
were brought into existence now what was
that state that they were in it was a
state of non-existence no knowledge of
anything Ecclesiastes 12:7 verifies it
says then shall the dust return to the
earth as it was and the spirit shall
return unto God who gave it what is it
that returns to God the breath not some
disembodied entity proof
check out Joel 34 verse 14 it says if he
said it's hard upon man if he gather
unto himself his spirit and his breath
all flesh shall perish together and man
shall turn again unto dust see man
returns to the condition he was in
before he was created and he
did not come from heaven he came from
the ground in Psalm 146 the Bible says
his breath goeth forth he returneth to
his earth in that very day his thoughts
perish he returns to the condition in
which he was in before he was created
Ecclesiastes 9:5 says this for the
living know that they shall die but the
dead know not anything neither have they
any more a reward for the memory of them
is forgotten also their love and their
hatred and their Envy is now perished
neither have they any more a portion for
ever in anything that is done under the
Sun look ezekiel 18:4 says this the soul
that sins it shall die so when people
say oh the soul can't die that's a
direct contradiction to what the Bible
teaches in Psalm 65 the Bible says for
in death there is no remembrance of thee
in the grave who shall give thee thanks
the dead cannot praise God the dead know
nothing at least according to the Old
Testament in psalm 115 17 the Bible says
the dead praise not the Lord neither any
that go down into silence verse after
verse after verse after verse verifies
what God said in Genesis 2 remember what
the Bible said about familiar spirits
God's prohibition on speaking to
familiar spirits is because those
spirits were really spirits of demons
not loved ones the Bible tells us that
Satan and his angels can perform
miracles that if possible could deceive
the very elect when we know that the
dead know nothing then we realized why
God is against the attempt to
communicate with the dead why because
the dead are dead they are not alive
they are in the grave the Bible
consistently defines death as asleep in
first Kings chapter 2 verse 10 the Bible
says so David slept with his fathers and
was buried in the City of David listen
over 36 times
in the book of kings and chronicles
alone the Bible uses the term slept with
his fathers to describe those who died
Daniel 12:1 the Bible says and at that
time shall Michael the Great Prince
which standeth for the children of his
people stand up and there shall be a
time of trouble such as never was since
there was a nation even to that same
time and at that time thy people shall
be delivered every one that shall be
found written in the book and then check
out verse 2 because there it says and
many of them that sleep in the dust of
the earth shall awake some to
everlasting life and some to shame and
everlasting contempt when Jesus returns
the Saints will arise from the grave
what condition were they in before that
they were sleeping conclusion the Old
Testament teaches nothing about the dead
really being alive no the dead are dead
okay so what about the New Testament
what does that teach in John 11 the
Bible speaks of a man named Lazarus who
died now Jesus raised Lazarus from the
dead and notice how Jesus himself
describes what happened to this soul or
person named Lazarus in John 11 11 he
saith unto them our friend Lazarus
sleepeth but I go that I may wake him
out of sleep then said his disciples
lord if he sleep he shall do well
howbeit Jesus speak of his death but
they thought he had spoken of taking of
rest in sleep then said Jesus unto them
plainly Lazarus is dead the New
Testament cannot contradict itself here
we have a reference in the New Testament
that death is the same thing that it was
in the Old Testament asleep is this
demonstrated elsewhere in the New
Testament listen John 5:25 jesus said
verily I say unto you that hour is
coming and now is when the dead shall
hear the voice of the Son of God and
they that hear
I live as in the old so in the new the
dead are in the grave not in heaven
okay what about Jesus where did he go
when he died listen the Bible tells us
that three days after his death when he
was resurrected jesus said to Mary in
John 20:17 touch me not for I am not yet
ascended to my father so he did not
ascend to heaven when he died okay well
did he go to hell listen in acts 2:27
speaking of Jesus the Bible says that
will not leave my soul in Hell neither
will vow to suffer thine Holy One to see
corruption that word Hell means the
grave Jesus went to the grief he was
dead
really and actually dead for three days
this is evidence that the thief on the
cross did not go to heaven because Jesus
himself had not yet ascended to heaven
now as I stated earlier while Jesus's
body was in the grave it would have been
crazy for anyone to believe that he was
in heaven the same is true today it is
absolutely illogical to say that a
person has gone to heaven or to a place
of torment at death while their body is
still in the grave in the book of Acts
Peter tells us that David the man after
God's own heart was still in the grave
and had not yet ascended this is after
the death burial and resurrection of
Jesus Christ acts 2:29 men and brethren
let me freely speak unto you of the
patriarch David that he is both dead and
buried and his Sepulchre is with us unto
this day acts 2 verse 34 for David is
not ascended into the heavens so david
has not yet ascended into heaven what
makes us think that others have I'm not
going to mention Moses and Elijah here
because I reference that in my first
video so go ahead and go back to that
video if you want to hear again what I
said about that but again the Bible is
clear
first Thessalonians 4:15 says this for
this we say unto you by the word of the
Lord that we which are alive and remain
unto the coming of the Lord shall not
prevent them which are asleep for the
Lord himself shall descend from heaven
with a shout with the voice of the
Archangel and with the Trump of God and
the dead in Christ shall rise first then
we which are alive and remain shall be
caught up together with them in the
clouds to meet the lord in the air and
so shall we ever be with the Lord this
verse clearly tells us that it is upon
resurrection not dead that we go to be
with Jesus okay so what about the story
of Lazarus and the rich man in which the
rich man goes to a burning place of
torment while Lazarus goes to heaven
remember the rich man asks for a drop of
water to cool his tongue to relieve his
suffering well I'll explain that by
using another verse second Corinthians
five six to eight absent from the body
present with the Lord these are the two
verses used by many people to teach that
the dead are really alive but these two
verses when taken together prove that
that position cannot possibly be true
remember those who use 2nd Corinthians 5
6 to 8 use it to teach that the dead
leave their bodies behind but their soul
lives on either in paradise or in
torment okay pause in the story of
Lazarus and the rich man the rich man is
a bodily in hell all would agree that he
is not bodily in hell right the story
says the rich man was buried so his body
is in the grave his body is on earth
it's clearly in the grave okay
then how is it that the rich man is
asking for water to cool his tongue
right do disembodied spirits have
tongues
how is it that he's lifting up his eyes
to see Lazarus do spirit have eyeballs
and how is it that Lazarus has fingers
to dip them in water to
who the rich man's tongue if Lazarus is
only in heaven in spirit while his body
is in the grave do you see the
contradiction disembodied spirits have
no physical fingers eyes or tongues you
see the answer to this dilemma is that
the story of Lazarus and rich man is a
parable now some object and say no
Lazarus was a real person because
parables don't name real people
therefore this is no parable well I
agree that Lazarus was a real person but
the question is who was this Lazarus and
how can this be a parable of Lazarus was
real so look why did Jesus use the name
Lazarus remember there was an account of
a real Lazarus which Jesus resurrected
from the dead right we just talked about
that a little bit earlier when the news
came to Jesus that Lazarus his friend
was dead the Bible says Jesus waited an
extra two days two days before going to
raise Lazarus his disciples were
wondering why he did this why didn't he
leave sooner and his response were that
was that this would be to glorify the
Son of God the death of that Lazarus
wouldn't glorify the Son of God so check
this out this means that Lazarus would
have been dead for three days and by the
time Jesus got to him to raise him from
the dead his resurrection would have
therefore occurred after three days and
three nights hmm okay so why did Jesus
wait because the Lazarus was to be a
symbol of the death burial and
resurrection of none other than Jesus so
when Jesus is giving this parable of
this guy named Lazarus he is speaking of
himself the rich man was a symbol of the
leaders of Israel who treated Jesus
symbolized as Lazarus in this parable as
nothing but a poor beggar they looked
upon Christ with contempt with that kind
of disdain
just as Lazarus died outside the gates
of the rich man
so Jesus died outside the gates of
Jerusalem the home the city of the rich
man and just as Lazarus was taken to the
bosom of the Father so Jesus at his
resurrection not his death at his
resurrection ascended to the bosom of
the heavenly Father in the parable the
rich man wants Lazarus to be raised from
the dead so that his brothers would
believe Abraham tells him listen they
have the Bible they have Moses and the
prophets and if they reject the Bible if
they reject Moses and the prophets they
will not believe even as even if one
were raised from the dead well guess
what Jesus did rise from the dead and
the rebellious leaders still refused to
believe the parable of the rich man was
not designed to teach that people go
straight to heaven or straight to hell
upon death but it was designed to teach
that if one rejects the Word of God they
will not believe even if God performed
the greatest miracle moreover remember
this Abraham like David is asleep in the
grief he could have no knowledge of
things going on on the earth so what
about this absent from the body and
present with the Lord thing well this is
very simple the body is mortal and
corruptible when Paul stated that he
longed to be absent from the body he was
not talking about death he was talking
about resurrection how do we know this
two verses up he says this for we that
are in this tabernacle do groan being
burdened not for that we would be
unclothed but clothed upon that
mortality might be swallowed up of life
in other words Paul is saying I can't
wait to have immortality that's what
he's saying I can't wait to get my new
body I can't wait till mortality becomes
immortality it is an assumption to
believe
he was saying that this transition
happens upon death Paul himself leaves
us no room to doubt what he was talking
about he was talking about resurrection
how do we know this
first Corinthians 15:51 the same Paul
wrote behold I show you a mystery we
shall not all sleep but we shall all be
changed in a moment in the twinkling of
an eye at the last Trump for the trumpet
shall sound and the dead shall be raised
incorruptible and we shall be changed
listen to this first Corinthians 15:50 3
for this corruptible must put on
incorruption and this mortal must put on
immortality so then when this
corruptible shall have put on
incorruption and this mortal shall have
put on immortality then shall be brought
to pass the saying that is written death
is swallowed up in victory
it is not upon death that the transition
from mortal to immortality occurs it is
upon resurrection listen carefully the
Christians hope is not death no one says
I can't wait to die
the Christians hope is a resurrection
death is an enemy no one who looks
forward to death saying I can't wait to
die so I can be with the Lord that's not
what Paul was saying Paul was saying I
cannot wait for the resurrection to have
a new body to have immortality swallow
up mortality so now we're going to go to
the last book in the Bible revelation
20:13 the Bible says and the sea and the
dead gave up the Dead which were in it
and death and he'll delivered up the
Dead which were in them and they were
judged every man according to their
works verse 14 says and death and he'll
were cast into the lake of fire this is
the second death listen carefully if the
wicked are burning in hell right now
what sense would it make for hell to be
thrown into the lake of fire
that word hell it is the same word that
is translated as grave in first
Corinthians 15:55 when Paul says old
grave where is thy victory
so in Revelation 20 when the Bible says
that hell is cast into a lake of fire
what it's saying is that death the grave
those who did not overcome those who
refused Christ in their lives those who
rejected the gospel who rejected God
then at the end of the 1000 years
according to Revelation chapter 20 then
is when hell begins to burn not before
so this brings us to our final point
which puts this whole idea of demons
being in charge of Hell a hell that is
burning now where it belongs as fiction
total error
it's the actual testimony not of a
person but of demons themselves
in Matthew chapter 8 Jesus has
confronted a man possessed with demons
when Jesus approaches this man the
demons make a startling and stunning
confession
the Bible says there met him two
possessed with Devils coming out of the
tombs exceeding fierce so that no man
might pass by that way and behold they
cried out saying what have we to do with
thee Jesus thou son of God are thou come
hither to torment us before the time
wait a minute did you catch that before
what time
you see what these demons have just
revealed is that demons are not in
charge of hell but rather they will
themselves be destroyed in hell this
picture of Satan being in charge of Hell
is pure fiction
now the Bible says that Satan himself
will be destroyed in the fires of hell
in Ezekiel 28 God says to Satan I will
destroy the or covering cherub from the
midst of the stones of fire
I will bring forth a fire from the midst
of thee it shall devour thee and I will
bring thee to ashes upon the earth in
the sight of all them that be holy so
look how fair would it be that the
originator of sin the devil and his
angels get to roam around free on earth
continuing to cause chaos and havoc in
ruin while humans who die go straight to
hell and therefore suffer longer than
Satan himself really not there's an
appointed time for Hellfire but that
time is not upon death listen this is
why Jesus said in Matthew 25 when the
Son of man cometh in his world and all
the holy angels with him then shall he
sit upon the throne of his glory and
before him shall be gathered all nations
and he shall separate them one from
another as a shepherd divides his sheep
from the goats he continues on in verse
41 then shall he say also unto them on
the left hand depart from me ye cursed
into everlasting fire prepared for the
devil and his angels did you catch that
it was not prepared for the devil and
his angels to rule over it was prepared
for the devil and his angels to be
destroyed in you see then at the end of
time not before listen these videos on
YouTube and these claims being made in
which people supposedly have gone to
hell and seeing this or that seen
rockstars and entertainers in hell it's
popular but they're all false
yes there's coming a time when the
wicked will suffer the penalties for
their sin but that time is not a death
it is at the end of the 1000 years these
so-called visions are not according to
the Word of God but rather according to
popular traditions to Hollywood Satan
works miracles to deceive if possible
the very elect of God so that they will
believe his original lie that the soul
is naturally immortal you shall not
surely die listen guys truth is never
popular and error is very easy to repeat
don't be a parrot of error
don't fall for what is popular stand for
what is true
if this video was helpful to you please
remember to Like and subscribe and I'll
see you next time
[Music]